Peter Bishop

720-272-5223 | pjb.den@gmail.com | Portfolio:

GitHub: https://github.com/Pierre81385 | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-bishop-46a51597/

CUNY Baruch College BBA in Economics ~ DU Full-Stack Certification

PROFILE

Full stack web developer with combined experience in the service industry and tech startups providing a balanced background of skills both customer-facing and technical. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from University of Denver Coding Bootcamp, and a Bachelors in Business Administration from the City University of New York at Baruch college with an emphasis on Economics. Strengths in client interaction, team collaboration, and a passion for backend development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, SWIFT

Applications: GitHub, MySQL, Xcode, Robo3T, MongoDB Atlas, Heroku, Salesforce, GraphQL

Tools: Express, Node.js, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, React, RESTful API's, JWT

PROJECTS

Favorite Recipes, Role: Backend developer, responsible for developing routes, creating backend to front end connections. GitHub: https://github.com/Pierre81385/adoptADog | Deployed Site: https://beautiful-haleakala-80520.herokuapp.com/

- Summary A project developing a full stack web application featuring JWT auth to allow logged in users to view, like, and choose dogs available for adoption.
- ? Tools JWT, React, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, Bootstrap

Weather Dashboard, Role: Sole developer

GitHub: https://github.com/TJCourey/beerMe-international | Deployed Site: https://tjcourey.github.io/beerMe-international/

- Summary A collaborative web app allowing users to find beers based on ABV and IBU preference and discover details about the beer and a random translation of how to order it.
- ? Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Punk and Funtranslations API's

EXPERIENCE

Bartender/Server/Barback | For[a]ged

March 2021 to Present

As a bartender at Foraged I also serve as the main bar back and bar server in a high-volume upscale environment. Developing positive customer relationships, ensuring responsible service and consistent craft cocktails. My role expands as needed to help ensure timely and reliable service with a team focus.

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted from food runner, to bar back, to server and full-time bartender within 6 months.
- Reliably receive 20%+ tips on average, with reliable sales, and a perfect record of on-time shifts with zero no-call, no shows.

General Manager | Sushi-Rama

June 2019 to August 2020

As the General Manager, responsibilities included overseeing all aspects of restaurant operations including but not limited to staffing, BOH and FOH ordering and inventory, balancing daily and weekly checkouts, entering invoices, and conducting payroll. Key Accomplishments:

- Steadily increased year-over-year sales and tracked this progress by developing a portfolio of spreadsheets to track and manage profit and loss, weekly inventory, cost of goods sold, product mix, and sales by guest count.
- Took charge of the basic administration of the company's web presence. Customizing sites for Sushi-rama, Osaka Ramen, and The Empire lounge. Developing signage, updating menus, and creating custom QR codes to adapt to the pandemic.
- Designed specialty cocktails and worked with the kitchen manager to design cost effective offerings to drive sales, clear inventory, and
 drive awareness of the restaurant and its products.
- Worked as needed as a manager, server, or host at all locations of Sushi-rama and Osaka Ramen.
- Obtained the ServSafe Manager, ServSafe Food Handler, and ServSafe COVID certifications.

Bartender | Mile High Spirits

July 2015 to June 2019

As a bartender at MHS, I served in a high-volume environment, developing positive customer relationships, ensuring customers were responsibly served and received consistent craft cocktails. Key Accomplishments:

- Additionally, worked in production canning, bottling, and responsible for making the Denver Dry Gin.
- Lead the distillery tour program, educating guests, explaining the distillation process, and leading guided tastings.
- Obtained TIPS certification, Merchant Guard license, and Pernod Ricard BarSmarts certification.

QA Analyst | Data Connect Corp

July 2012 to February 2018

As a QA Analyst, I tested software release features on iOS, Windows, and cloud-based systems relating to an event management product. Working with JIRA for case management. Ran all database scripts on client databases to move them from testing to show ready. Key Accomplishments:

- Assisted with staff and equipment logistics, hiring just-in-time staff, developing hardware inventory systems, and conducting regular training to improve staff skills.
- Traveled regularly to events as a Team Leader, overseeing hardware and software deployment, executing over \$655,000 in show day
 services across more than 30 events per year. Provided live demos and training on our software and services to groups as large as
 300, and custom reports on demand with SQL database queries to compile event statistics.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Full Stack Web Development Certificate, 2021

Program focused on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS